Lycopodiumの病理は、人をオープンで外交的にし大胆に見せますが、内的には不安や弱さを感じます。特に「権威」と対峙した場合にそうなります。
臆病になります。つまりLycopodiumは２つの顔を持つのです。とてもくつろぎ、大胆でジョークをいう大物。
少し年配の方はムッソリーニを覚えていますか？勇ましい演説をする独裁者で、常にい膨満していました。
ガスが多く風船のように。その裏にはエネルギーが欠如しているのです。
そしてこの外観は異性の前で顕著になります。女好きの男。女好きという言葉を知っていますか？
女性は皆、Lycopodiumに落ちますね。これです。これを欲するのです。「責任の欠如」が好きなのです。
責任を負いたくないのです。だから責任を負わなくて済むような行動をするのです。
多くの場合は男性レメディーです。一晩限りの関係を望む男性です。
次は違う女性と一晩か二晩限りの関係で責任がなく、愛着も深い関係もありません。
Lycopodiumにはありません。もし関係を築き、家族ができ妻と２人の子供と多大な責任を負っている事に気付くと
内面で非常に恐れが出て来て、時には家族を捨てることさえあります。全てのLycopodiumがそうするわけではありませんが、裏にはこのような考えがあるのです。
「これは俺には手に負えない」という思いです。
だから「楽しみだけで責任は負わない」、という事が彼らには重要です。
だから一晩限りの関係を求めるレメディーとして知られているのです。皆さんの所に来た時には、皆さんの秘書を口説くでしょう。
秘書はだいたい若い女性ですね。彼らは口説きます。自分を大物に見せ「電話番号は？」と。
でも中に入ると全く違った態度です。怖がって、臆病です。
あるケースを思い出します。Lycopodiumだと感じていました。背が低い男性でした。私は「臆病ですか？」と聞きました。
彼は「ええ！ある話をしますから、臆病かどうか先生が判断してください」と。
「ギリシャ陸軍にいた時に共産主義者の反政府活動があり、森で戦っていました」 彼は陸軍に所属していたのです。
「ある時点で、私たちは共産主義者によって包囲されてしまい、隊員が全て捕まってしまったのです。私以外は。」
「なぜ私は捕まらなかったのかわかりますか？」「いいえ」「包囲されているのが判明した時に急いで逃げたら、地面に大きな割れ目があり、向こうまで５Ｍほどもあったのです」
「戦士として様々な持ち物があったのですが、私はただ一人、恐怖のあまり向こう側にジャンプしたのです。想像できますか？」と。
「とてつもない恐怖から、私は跳ばずにはいられなかったのです。他の誰もジャンプしませんでした」
「私は残存した軍隊に辿りつき、大佐は表彰してくれました。捕まらなかった英雄だ、と」
「でも自分がなぜ捕まらなかったのかを知っている」と。これはLycopodiumの内側の臆病さがどれほど強いものなのかを示すものです。
しかし「弱者の前ではエゴが肥大する」 だから私は「独裁者」と表現するのです。内弁慶の子供は独裁者のように振る舞いますね。
でも学校では非常に良い子です。話しもしません。悪い事はしない。とてもおとなしく従順です。
そして自分の力を出せる所に戻ると独裁者になるのです。
このレメディーは主に消化器系、胆嚢に影響し、大量のガスを作ります。
朝起きると膨満しています。悪化の時間帯は１６～２０時です。
これは非常に確立された症状です。午後の４～８時にとても気分が悪くなり、気が沈み、落ち込み、膨満します。
エネルギーが無くなり、イライラし、何もしたくなくなるのです。頭は働きません。
この時間帯に肺や肝臓の働きが低下します。
ここに「性的過剰によるインポテンツ」とあります。このような男女関係を得ようとする男性を想像して下さい。
何が起こるかというと、何か新しいもので無いと興奮しなくなるのです。
それ以上は興奮できないので、３５～３８歳頃に結婚しても３か月後には完全にインポテンツになってしまうのです。
もしくは、「この５年間、妻とのセックスはありません」と言うかもしれません。
妻を愛していて、一緒にいて楽しくても性的には興奮できません。これまでの表面的なセックスのせいです。
表面的なセックスは性欲を殺してしまうのです。だから今日の若者は１６～２０歳でもインポテンツなのです。
これが理由です。性的開放運動により、この世代がセックスで遊び過ぎたのです。１２～１３歳の少女でも彼氏がいなくてはならないのです。少なくともアメリカではそうです。
ドイツではどれ程かわかりませんが、恐らくまだでしょう。ルーマニア、彼女が困惑しているのがわかりますね。ルーマニアではこれらの事は起きていませんね。
でも１２～１４歳で始めるのです。１９歳までには全てを経験し、知っています。そして何も気にしない致命的な女性になるのです。
反対にインドでは、男女は婚前の性交は許されていませんから、９５％もの婚姻が維持するのです。男女共に結婚してから初体験をするからです。
このような夫婦関係は長続きします。でも片方や両方が婚前に多くの経験があると、Lycopodiumやその他のレメディーの状態になります。
インポテンツや無関心、もはや興奮しません。その婚姻はすぐに破たんします。なぜなら興奮させてくれる相手を探すからです。
Lycopodium、Staphysagria、Agnus-cactusはインポテンツの主な３つのレメディーです。それぞれ違う理由からですが。
Lycopodiumのインポテンツの原因は話しましたね。
StaphysagriaはStaphysagriaの回に話します。
「早漏」「性交中に勃起が低下」 なぜ早漏になるかわかりますか？
それは彼が女たらしだからです。だから最初は非常に興奮するのですぐにオーガズムに達します。性交の前でさえも。
「夜にお腹が減る」レメディーです。でもそれ程でもありません。「食事中に食欲が増す」
They sit down to eat, they eat a little bit and appetite is gone, that's one thing. Or they sit down to eat, no appetite and they start eating and appetite comes. So they have both.
Desire for sweets is quite strong and desire for warm drinks also is quite strong element for Lycopodium.
If you think he is a Lycopodium, for instance, and he says I have thirst for cold drinks, you think twice before you give it.
That point is quite important for Lycopodium.
Another thing is emaciation of upper part of the body, they are emaciating here very much, losing flesh. The bottom part becomes big and especially the belly.
It's bloated, mostly air, balloon.
You saw these strong wrinkles in her forehead? Lycopodium is one of the remedies you will think when you have this special kind of worry that produces this kind of wrinkles.
Another very characteristic thing is heels cracked. The heels are dry and with big cracks without much pain. There is another remedy that has that, it's Calcarea Fluorica.
One foot hot and the other cold, that is another peculiar symptom. In bed they will touch the feet and one is cold, the other is hot.
Very strange, they have it Pulsatilla and Chelidonium also have that.
Impossible to sleep on left side like Lachesis. Lachesis and Lycopodium and Phosphorus can not sleep on left side.
-Are there special worries that makes this kind of wrinkles in the forehead? Do you know that ?
-I don't know. You see in fever especially the nostrils go in and out.
-Now we learn the Chelidonium and the Lycopodium. Do you think is now the time to learn the different diagnosis between them, both?
-You must tell me. Aversion to cold drinks. Aversion for cheese, sometimes is also desire. Sometimes in the remedies you have polarities.
For instance in Natrum Muriaticum you have desire for salt and you have aversion for salt also.
So they get polarities. Sometimes I have seen Calcarea Carbonica with aversion to eggs.
It means disturbance of the calcium but taking a lot of calcium doesn't need more. It says, no, no calcium I don't need.
They have diarrhea and then they have constipation some other people.
Lycopodium they need company. They are afraid of the dark, afraid to be alone in the house in the night, this cowardice.
The Israelis are correcting me, the Maltese are correcting me, the Germans are correcting me and here are the English who are not correcting me. Let me hear it once from the original.
Cowardice. Did I say it correctly? Say it in the American way. Cowardice, but I will forget it.
If you get it wrongly from the beginning, forget it.
A man 45, 50 stays in the house even little children are gone and he is alone. The mother took the children and they are gone and he is going to sleep in the night.
The night comes and my god, there is nobody in the house. It's not only that they are afraid of some spooky things, they are also afraid of ghosts and things like that.
But this is a feeling inside, I'm alone in the night. Not in my house where I live in the wilderness where you can not see any house all around, on a flat, on an apartment, next door.
Even if there is a child inside, they feel secure.
As long as there is somebody in the next room, if the child is sleeping in the next room, they feel secure.
The moment they feel alone, that gives you the idea of cowardice.
Mostly they are afraid of the dark and being alone. They want company.
-You said most of them are women. I have a woman Lycopodium and they have fear of men, they are afraid of men.
-You see if you get a case like this or a case like that, special cases where women have been harassed, they have been raped, abused and things like that, especially these cases are terrible.
You can not expect to have desire for men.
-I had a woman that it was so high, I put it in the computer 4 times, fear of men. She was very bloated and I gave her 200. She said nothing changed and I said, we go to the computer again. I said, fear of men is still so high?
She said, no, no I have a boyfriend now. This is gone. In 4 weeks with Lycopodium.
-It is true that fear of men as you put fear of people, they are afraid of people. You have this symptom as a fear with Lycopodium, the same way as with Hyoscyamus, fear of people.
But at the same time, they need somebody to rely upon, they have anxiety about health, they are hypochondriacs. They can become so anxious about their health, totally hypochondriac.
Many times I have seen cases that they have much less symptoms than I have and they come to be treated.
I have a little pain in here, I say forget it. Live with this little pain here and there but the anxiety is so much that they can not live, it just simply is impossible for them to exist with this little bit of something.
There are a lot of differences. First of all the Chelidonium does not have this fear at all. These fears I mentioned, are not there.
On the contrary they are people down the earth without fears, having gallbladder problems but no bloated.
The problem is more inflammations of the gallbladder than the amount of bile that goes into the guts.
Lycopodium has a disturbance of the bile that is going into the colon and then you have the zymosis and then you have the bloatness.
With Chelidonium the effect is more on the gallbladder and the liver. They are not coward, they are not sexually driven.
Lycopodium is sexually driven.
You can not confuse them actually. Lycopodium after treatment is taking more responsibility or it will stay with that trait afterwards?
Yes he can take more responsibility. The fear is gone. Of course there is a special type of person who shuns responsibility to such an extend that he will just, one day, leave everything behind and disappear.
That is not going to change his character so much but they attain more self confidence. Underneath is a lack of self confidence.
That the woman will say, bye, bye or that you are impotent or this or that.
Here with Magnesia Carbonica. The Magnesias, the Chelidonium, the Lycopodium are affecting the digestive system primarily.
The Magnesias in general are people who do not like controversy, who do not like fighting.
They are the peace movement people, peace under any price. Magnesia Carbonica and Magnesia Muriatica have this trait.
We don't know how the gallbladder is affecting the guts (?) . We say this person does not have guts and the other day we say, he has gall, he has power.
Magnesia Carbonica does not have. Another characteristic of this remedy is the body smells sour.
Another characteristic is that milk brings on diarrhea, makes the person worse, brings constipation, anything.
Milk passes undigested. It feels as if not loved by parents. Children who feel they are forsaken.
That means my mother loves better my brother. My father loves better my sister.
Who believe that but they will not fight to gain a position in the heart of the parents.
No controversy. A great characteristic is that corasea (?) starts before menses, the nose starts running, the eyes start running as if he has a cold.
Then the menses go away and it's finished. That is just before menses, during menses and then, well.
If you have that, it's very characteristic.
Menses flow more profusely at night. Menses are flowing; when they are getting up and walk menses are retracting.
Craving for meat even in children and aversion to vegetables. They almost will say, never I eat vegetables, I'm not interested.
Aversion to vegetables you think it's nothing but it's very important symptom because everybody eats vegetables, like vegetables.
If you find somebody who will say I never eat vegetables, then immediately your mind goes to Magnesia Carbonica.
Unrefreshed sleep is common to all Magnesias, to Lycopodium as well, to Lachesis and Phosphorus. Especially unrefreshing sleep is connecting with misfunction of the liver.
Misfunction of the liver makes you feel very unrefreshed in the morning.